Jascha Heifetz Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Miscellaneous, 1901-1991 (Box 257-258, Box 272, Box 275-279)
  - Posters
    - Posters 1911, 1938, n.d., Rolls BOXES: 276-279 (Box 258, Box 276-279)
London: Kegan Paul, French, Trubner and Co, Ltd., 1919
de Saussine, Renée
Paganini
Translated by Marjorie Laurie
New York: McGraw Hill, 1954
Schubert, Franz
Franz Schubert's letters and other writings
Edited by Otto Erich Deutsch
Translated by Venetia Savile
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1928
Schumann, Robert
Music and musicians, 2 vols.
Translated and edited by Fanny Raymond Ritter
London: William Reeves, 1891
Schweitzer, Albert
J. S. Bach, 2 vols.
Translated by Ernest Newman
New York: Macmillan, 1952
Seroff, Victor I.
Rachmaninoff
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1950
Takeshita, Hiroshi
Gakki shushi kaisetsu [Explanations to choice collections of musical instruments]
Kyoto: Uchida Bijutsu Shoshi, Showa 4 1929
Thompson, Oscar
Debussy: man and artist
New York: Tudor, 1940
Toye, Francis
Rossini: a study in tragi-comedy
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1947
Veinus, Abraham
The concerto
New York: Doubleday, 1944
Wagner, Richard
Gesammelte Schriften und Dichtungen, 6 vols.
Edited by Wolfgang Golther
Berlin: Deutsches Verlagshaus Bong & Co., [1913]
Walter, Bruno
Theme and variations
Translated by James A. Galston
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1947
Wellesz, Egon, ed.
Ancient and oriental music
The New Oxford History of Music
London: Oxford University Press, 1957
White, A. W.
The violin: how to construct from beginning to completion
Boston, Press of the Inquirerer, 1892
Wilder, Victor
Mozart: the story of his life as man and artist according to authentic documents..., 2 vols.
Translated by L. Liebich
London: William Reeves, [1908?]
Winternitz, Emanuel
Musical instruments of the western world
New York: McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1966
Yorke-Long, Alan
Music at court: four eighteenth century studies
London: Weidenfeld and Nicolson, 1954
Zarate, Leon
Sarasate
Barcelona: Ediciones Ave, 1945
American guild of musical artists
Agreement Constitution and By-Laws
New York, September 1949
American numismatic society
American Journal of Numismatics, with Index by Author and Subject, Volumes 1-50 (1808-1916), and to the proceedings of The American Numismatic Society
New York: American Numismatic Society, 1917
Musique brésilienne
Rio de Janeiro, 1937
National association of artists
Largest collections of modern paintings in Italy
Florence: National Association of Artists, 1930
Ukazy po monetmony i medal'nomy delu v Rossii: alfabitnyi ukazatel' imen i predmetov [Decrees regarding monetary affairs in Russia: alphabetical index of names and subjects]
Publishers of the former Prince Georgii Mikhailovich, n.d.
[S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d.
Appendix III: Books Returned to the Jascha Heifetz Estate
Auer, Leopold
Violin playing as I teach it
New York: Frederick A. Stokes, 1921
Reprint, Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott, 1960
Benoist, Andre
The accompanist: an autobiography of Andre Benoist
Edited by John Anthony Maltese
Neptune, New Jersey: Paganiniana Publications, 1978
Calvocoressi, M.D. and Gerald Abraham
Masters of Russian music
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1936
Camner, James, ed.
The great instrumentalists in historic photographs
New York: Dover Publications, 1980
Chapin, Schuyler
Musical chairs: a life in the arts
New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1977
Chasins, Abraham
Speaking of pianists
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1957
Chotzinoff, Samuel
Toscanini: an intimate portrait
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1956
Cooke, Charles
Playing the piano for pleasure
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1941
Downes, Olin
Olin Downes on music
Edited by Irene Downes
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1957
Erskine, John, ed.
A musical companion
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1935
My life in music
New York: William Morrow & Company, 1950
Ewen, David
A journey to greatness: the life and music of George Gershwin
New York: Henry Holt and Company, 1956
Men and women who make music
New York: Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1939
Men and women who make music
Revised Edition
New York: Merlin Press, Inc., 1949
Gershwin, Ira
Lyrics on several occasions
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1959
Gottschalk, Louis Moreau
Notes of a pianist
Edited by Jeanne Behrend
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1964
Hadden, J. Cuthbert
Composers in love and marriage
London: John Long, Limited, 1913
Hanslick, Eduard
Vienna's golden years of music: 1850-1900
Translated and Edited by Henry Pleasants III
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1950
Hasland-Christensen, Henning
The music of the mongols, part I: eastern Mongolia
Stockholm: [Tryckeri aktiebolaget Thule], 1943
Huneker, James Gibbons
Intimate letters of James Gibbons Huneker
Edited by Josephine Huneker
New York: Boni and Liveright, 1924
Jacob, H. E.
Johan Strauss, father and son
Translated by Margueritte Wolf
[New York]: Greystone Press, 1939
Jalas, Margareta, ed
Jean Sibelius
Helsinki: Otava Publishing Co., 1952
Johnson, Gerald W.
A little night music: discoveries in the exploitation of an art, 5th ed.
[S.l]: Harper & Brothers, 1937
Johnson, Harold E.
Jean Sibelius
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1959
Komroff, Manuel
The magic bow: a romance of Paganini
New York: Harper & Brothers, 1940
Lachmann, Erich
The Erich Lachmann collection of stringed instruments
Los Angeles: University of Southern California, 1950
Landowska, Wanda
Landowska on music
Edited and translated by Denise Restout
New York: Stein and Day, 1965
Levant, Oscar
A smattering of ignorance
New York: Doubleday, Doran & Co., Inc., 1940
Leyda, Jay and Sergei Bertensson, eds.
The Musorgsky reader
New York: W.W, Norton, 1947
McNamara, Daniel I., ed.
The ASCAP biographical dictionary of composers, authors and publishers, 2nd ed.
New York: Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1952
Nestyev, Israel V.
Sergei Prokofiev: his musical life
Translated by Rose Prokofieva
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1946
Niecks, Frederick
A concise dictionary of musical terms, 2nd ed.
London: Augener, Ltd., [1884]
Norman, Gertrude and Miriam Lubell Shrifte, eds.
Letters of composers: an anthology (1603-1945)
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1946
O'Connell, Charles
The Victor book of the symphony
New York: Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1934
Peyser, Ethel
The house that music built: Carnegie Hall
New York: Robert M. McBride and Company, 1936
Pleasants, Henry
The agony of modern music
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1955
de Pourtalès, Guy
Franz Liszt (l'homme d'amour)
Translated by Elanor Stimson Brooks
New York: Henry Holt and Company, 1926
Radio Corporation of America
A catalog of the music America loves best
Camden, New Jersey: RCA, September 1950
A catalog of the music America loves best
Camden, New Jersey: RCA, March 1953
A catalog of RCA Victor records
Camden, New Jersey: RCA, 1948
A complete catalog of Victor records for 1940-41
Camden, New Jersey: RCA, 1940
Rimsky-Korsakov, Nicolai
Practical manual of harmony
Translated by Joseph Achron
New York: Carl Fischer, 1930
Rolland, Romain
Beethoven
Translated by B. Constance Hull
New York: Henry Holt and Co., 1927
Saint-Foix, Georges
The symphonies of Mozart
Translated by Leslie Orrey
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1949
Schauffler, Robert Haven
Franz Schubert: the Ariel of music
New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1949
Schillinger, Joseph
The Schillinger system of musical composition, 2 vols.
New York: Carl Fischer, 1946
Schindler, Kurt
Folk music and poetry of Spain and Potugal
New York: Hispanic Institute, 1941
Schumann, Robert
Gesammelte Schriften über Musik und Musiker, 2 vols.
Leipzig: Georg Wigand's Verlag, 1854
Slonimsky, Nicolas
Thesaurus of scales and melodic patterns
New York: Coleman-Ross, 1947
Spaeth, Sigmund
Stories behind the world's great music
New York: Whittlesey House, 1937
Spitta, Philipp
The life of Bach, 3 vols. (Only 2 vols.)
Translated by Clara Bell and J.A. Fuller Maitland
London: Novello and Gray, 1899
Strauss, Richard
Recollections and reflections
Edited by Willi Schuh
Translated by L.J. Lawrence
London: Boosey & Hawkes, 1953
Stravinsky, Igor and Robert Craft
Conversations with Igor Stravinsky
Garden City: Double day & Company, 1959
Szigeti, Joseph
With strings attached, 2d ed.
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1967
Taubman, Howard
Music as a profession
New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1939
Music on my beat
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1943
Tawaststjerna, Erik
Sibelius, volume I
Translated by Robert Layton
London: Faber and Faber, 1976
Thayer, Alexander Wheelock
The life of Ludwig van Beethoven
[S.l.]: The Beethoven Association, 1921
Thompson, Sylvia
Unfinished symphony
Boston: Little, Brown, and Company, 1933
Tovey, Donald Francis
Essays in musical analysis, 6 vols.
London: Oxford University Press, 1935
Turner, W. J.
Mozart: the man and his works
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1938
Veinus, Abraham
Victor book of concertos
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1948
Weinstock, Herbert
Handel
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1946
Chopin
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1949
Wierzynski, Casmir
The life and death of Chopin
Translated by Norbert Guterman
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1949
Wise, James Waterman
The Jew in American life
New York: Julian Messner, 1946
Appendix IV: Sound Recordings Transferred to M/B/RS
10 in. LP's
Decca DL 5214
LBM 7055
LM 7017
LM-163
LS 107
RCA A. 330.202
Victor LCT-6
Victor LM 127
Victor LM 163
Victor LM 18
Victor LM 4
Victor LM 60
Victor LM 71
Victor LS 101
Victor LS 110
La Vois de Son Maitre FBLP 1008
12 in. LP'S
A12R 0263
Decca DL 8521
Decca DL9760
EP- 3028
No Co. 630285
Seraphim 60162
Seraphim 60221
Seraphim 60230
Seraphim 60230
Victor 1010
Victor 1015
Victor 1021
Victor 30,032
Victor 630 353
Victor 7708-2RC
Victor A 630 250 [2 copies]
Victor A 630 223 [2 copies]
Victor A12R 0221
Victor AGL1-4949 [2 copies]
Victor ARM4-0942
Victor ARM4-0943
Victor ARM4-0944
Victor ARM4-0945
Victor ARM4-0946
Victor ARM4-0947
Victor ARM4-0947
Victor CRL6-0720
Victor CRL6-0720
Victor CRM6-2264
Victor ERB 21(2)
Victor ERB 7055
Victor LCT 1016
Victor LCT 1017
Victor LCT 1020
Victor LCT 1022
Victor LCT 1043
Victor LCT-1113
Victor LCT-1122
Victor LCT-1150
Victor LCT-1160
Victor LDS 2513 [2 copies]
Victor LM 1022
Victor LM 1022
Victor LM 1051
Victor LM 1090
Victor LM 1111
Victor LM 1119
Victor LM 1120
Victor LM 1121
Victor LM 1166
Victor LM 1184
Victor LM 1782
Victor LM 1818
Victor LM 1903
Victor LM 1903 [boxed set]
Victor LM 1992 [boxed set]
Victor LM 1992
Victor LM 2115
Victor LM 2550
Victor LM 2734
Victor LM 2740
Victor LM 2836
Victor LM 2860
Victor LM/LSC 2652RE
Victor LM-1193
Victor LM-1782
Victor LM-1818 [2 copies]
Victor LM-1832
Victor LM-1842
Victor LM-1861
Victor LM-1903
Victor LM-1912
Victor LM-1914
Victor LM-1931
Victor LM-1958
Victor LM-1976
Victor LM-2027 [2 copies]
Victor LM-2034
Victor LM-2050
Victor LM-2069
Victor LM-2089
Victor LM-2115
Victor LM-2149
Victor LM-2180
Victor LM-2186
Victor LM-2210
Victor LM-2314
Victor LM-2382
Victor LM-2435
Victor LM-2563
Victor LM-2770 [2 copies]
Victor LM-2856 [2 copies]
Victor LM-2860
Victor LM-2909
Victor LM-2919
Victor LM-2973
Victor LM-2985
Victor LM-6707 [2 copies]
Victor LM-7025 (2)
Victor LM-9007
Victor LM-9014
Victor LM-9016
Victor LS 2037
Victor LS 2043
Victor LS 2055
Victor LS 2059
Victor LS-2005
Victor LS-2017
Victor Ls-2034
Victor LSC 2577
Victor LSC 3048
Victor LSC 3233
Victor LSC 4017
Victor LSC-1992
Victor LSC-2128
Victor LSC-2129 [2 copies]
Victor LSC-2550
Victor LSC-2730
Victor LSC-2734
Victor LSC-2737
Victor LSC-2856 [2 copies]
Victor LSC-2867
Victor LSC-2957
Victor LSC-2978
Victor LSC-3009
Victor LSC-3048
Victor LSC-3068
Victor LSC-3109
Victor LSC-3205
Victor LSC-3232
Victor LSC-3235
Victor LSC-3255
Victor LSC-3265
Victor LVT-1035
Victor LVT-1035
Victor RB 16009
Victor RB-16218
Victor SRA 2027 [1 disc in slipcase]
Victor VCM-7067(2)
Victor VCS-7058(2)
Victor VCS-7087
LP'S not found in OCLC
Columbia ML 2112
Seraphim 601230
Seraphim 60230
Victor 30,032
Victor 630285
Victor 630353
Victor A 330202
Victor A 630223
Victor A 630250
Victor A12R 0221
Victor A12R 0263
Victor L 16064
Victor LM 127
Victor LM 1782 [Germany]
Victor LM 18
Victor LM 1818 [Germany]
Victor LM 1818 [Argentina]
Victor LM 2050
Victor LM 4
Victor LM 6
Victor LM 60
Victor LM 7055
Victor LS 101
Victor LS 107
Victor LS 110
Victor LS 2017
Victor LS 2034
Victor LS 2037
Victor LS 2043
Victor LS 2055
Victor LS 2059
Victor RB 16009
Victor RB 16218
Victor SRA 2027
La Voix de Son Maitre FBLP 1008
45 RPM'S
Victor 45NC 0047
Victor 49-3312 Hora Staccato
Victor A 95 225
Victor EP-3005
Victor EP-3023
Victor EP-3038
Victor EP-3066
Victor EP-3078
Victor EP-8001
Victor EP-8003
Victor ERA-126
Victor ERA-184
Victor ERA-214
Victor ERA-214 [Chilean pressing]
Victor ERA-240
Victor ERA-57
Victor ERA-71
Victor ERA-94
Victor ES-8006
Victor FS-12
Victor Test Pressing Hora Staccato
Victor WCT-14 [2]
Victor WCT-21
Victor WCT-22
Victor WCT-25
Victor WCT-27
Victor WCT-28
Victor WCT-30
Victor WCT-71 [2]
Victor WDM-1158
Victor WDM-1183
Victor WDM-1240
Victor WDM-1254
Victor WDM-1267
Victor WDM-1283
Victor WDM-1290
Victor WDM-1385
Victor WDM-1442
Victor WDM-1486
Victor WDM-1487
Victor WDM-1488
Victor WDM-1499
Victor WDM-1511
Victor WDM-1515
Victor WDM-1523
Victor WDM-1592
Victor WDM-1603
Victor WDM-1642
Victor WDM-1658
Victor WDM-9007
Victor WDM-9014
Victor WEPR 9
Victor 49-0278
Victor 49-0450
Victor 49-0626
Victor 49-0668
Victor 49-0884
Victor 49-1294
Victor 49-3305
Victor 49-3443
Victor 49-3611
Victor 49-3612
Victor 49-3634
Victor 49-3782
Victor G7Nh [damaged]
78 RPM'S
M 827
Victor 0087-89
Victor 18-0179-80
Victor
12 Miscellaneous 12" 78's in container. The record numbers follow in the order they appear in the container: D.B. 2846, 14369, 8759, 6848, 8420, 74635, 8828, 6510, 6376, 6159, 6491
7 in. Reel to Reel Audio Tapes
Victor ECS 4 [2]
Victor DCS 64
Victor FCS 24
Victor 0291-IS [matrix] From NBC Symphony performance list [Apr. 9, 1944]: [on same program with Wagner's Parsifal-Prelude, & Good Friday Spell]
NCP 989/990
Office of War Information- Voice of America Music from America- Symphonic Series Program #5